嘿, 伙计!
Hey,guys!
我想他跑掉了
Guess he got away.
小脚丫子可以出来玩玩么?
Can baby shoes come out to play?
快点
Come on.
手放头上, 爬出来
Hands on your head,climb out.
如果手放在头上, 我爬不出来
I can't climb out if my hands are on my head.
就把手放在我可以看见的地方, 伙计
Just keep 'em where i can see 'em,man.
照做. 照做. 快点
Go 'head. Go 'head.Come on.
你比较兴奋, 当差的?
You high,popo?
是的, 伙计
Yeah,man.
抓蠢人让我很兴奋
Catchin' morons makes me high.
抓住衣领把衬衫脱下来, 然后转过来
Take your shirt off by your collar and turn around.
喔, 看看啊!
Whoo,would you  look at that!
小子还有家伙
Dude's got a weapon.
好的, 你有权利保持...愚蠢!
All right,you have the right to remain...stupid!
小心走火
Watch the gun.
你所说的一切没有人可以理解
Anything you say will be completely incomprehensible.
认真的, 伙计, 小心点!
Seriously,man,careful!
认真, 伙计? 认真?
Seriously,man?Seriously?
你妈妈可知道你干的好事!
Your mama know what you do?!
啊...真好
Aww...that's sweet.
- 你爸爸很自豪. 你上了当地报纸了,- 因为我的文章
Your dad's proud.You made the local paper.,--From my article.
消停一下吧
Give it a rest.
你看了他在补白写的东西了么?
You read what he wrote in the margin?
"我的朋友拉撒路(圣经)睡去,但我能把他唤醒"
"Our friend lazarus sleeps,but I go that i may wake him up."
他不是为我自豪, 他是为耶稣自豪
He's not proud of me.He's proud of jesus.
我做对的任何事, 都是上帝的功劳
Everything I do right is god's work.
我做错的任何事, 都是他妈我自己的错
Everything I do wrong is my own damn fault.
有幽默感的警察
Cop with a sense of humor.
鉴别诊断
Differential diagnosis.
他还在急救室里, 血流不止
Guy's in the E.R.,Bleeding on everybody.
磕药?
Drugs?
他是个警察
He's a cop.
说的好. 警察不会...磕药?
Good point.How about...drugs?
毒品检测没有显示问题
Tox screen was clean.
他被一颗子弹击中了
He did,however,get hit by a bullet.
顺便提一下
Just mentioning it.
他被人射击了?
He was shot?
难不成子弹是被人扔过去的?
No,somebody threw it at him.
首先考虑外伤,子弹碎片弹进他的脑子
I'm thinking trauma.He's got bullet fragments lodged in his brain.
照小脚丫子说,警察在中枪之前就一直在笑
According to baby shoes,the cop was laughing before he got shot.
小脚丫子?
Baby shoes?
- 朝他开枪的家伙, - 可靠的证人
--Guy who shot him.--Reliable witness.
他叫小脚丫子, 他能有多坏?
His name is baby shoes.How bad can he be?
碎片在脑子里面待错地方,引发了欣快症
Fragments are in the wrong part of the brain to cause euphoria.
扩大搜索范围,查查咳嗽原因和浑浊的肺
So let's expand the search.Factor in the cough and the cloudy lungs.
- 为什么不在意心率加快?,- 因为他在休克中
Why are we ignoring the elevated heart rate?--'Cause he's in shock.
会不会他在中枪之前, 心率已经很快了?
What if the heart was already fast before he got shot?
你指在追犯人之后?
You mean after the foot race?
他有些眩晕, 表明供氧受到阻碍
He's giddy.Indicates a blockage of oxygen.
一氧化碳同时会使心率升高
Carbon monoxide gas would elevate the heart rate
还会导致咳嗽以及伤害神经功能
and cause coughing and impair neurological functions.
他在户外一氧化碳中毒?
He got co poisoning outdoors?
是的
Yeah.
因为那些混蛋没有签署京都议定书,(京都议定书旨在限制全球温室气体排放)
All 'cause those bastards didn't ratify kyoto.
或者他是在户内一氧化碳中毒
Or he got co poisoning indoors
在没有吸入足量倒毙之前, 他到了户外
and moved outdoors before he'd inhaled enough to make him drop dead.
测一下他动脉一氧化碳含量,如果一氧化碳血红蛋白水平高过15%
Test his arterial blood gas.If his carboxy hemoglobin levels are higher than 15%,
就把他送进高压氧舱
stick him in a hyperbaric chamber.
你去检查警车的气体泄漏
You go check the cop car for gas leaks or--
如果是警车出问题, 他的搭档也会病的
if it was the cop car,his partner would be sick.
嗯, 也许她是病了,只不过她幽默感没那么强
Well,maybe she is she just doesn't have as good a sense of humor.
还有检查他的私人用车, 工作场所, 家里
Also check his personal cars,work,home.
我会检查警察分局
I'll check the precinct.
血液测试证明你有轻度的一氧化碳中毒
Blood tests confirm you have low-level carbon monoxide poisoning.
要送你去高压氧舱...
We're putting you inside a high-pressure chamber to...
你不是很在乎, 是么?
You don't really care,do you?
你家附近有燃气供应站么?
Do you live near a gas supply?
有, 我本人就是
Uh,yeah,me.
吃过一个巨型玉米卷饼之后
After,like,a huge enchilada.
有没有把有毒物质放在家里?
Anything toxic you have at your home?
诸如油漆溶剂, 不卫生的?
Any paint solvents,anything unhygienic?
唔, 没有
Uh,no.
没有, 我家里保持得很干净
No,I keep a pretty clean home.
如果呼吸困难, 你可以按这个钮
If you start having trouble breathing,you can press this button,
这个舱就会减压
and the chamber will decompress.
像这样?
Like this?
不是现在. 是你有麻烦的时候
Don't now.If you have trouble.
啊, 它坏了
Ah,it's broken.
好吧, 如有你有麻烦, 我们替你按
All right,well,if you have problems we'll push it for you.
肌肉痉挛
Muscle contracture.
觉得有多痛?
How bad does it hurt?
不痛...一点不痛
Not...not at all.
看上去很吓人, 哈?
Looks wild,though,huh?
大脑供氧不足. 你正在丧失运动能力
Your brain's not getting enough oxygen.You're losing motor function.
必须马上开始
We should start this right away.
我应该害怕么?
Should I be scared?
不, 可能在你待的地方有一氧化碳泄漏
No,you probably have a carbon monoxide leak in your place.
有人到那里去查了
We have a guy there checking things out.
看起来没问题
Sounds okay.
煤气阀门怎么样?
How about the gas intake valve?
没一点问题
Looks great.
阀门在炉子间里
It's down in the furnace room.
设备没有问题
Your system's fine.
如果有一氧化碳泄漏,半数的警员会病倒
If you had a carbon monoxide leak,half the force would be sick.
那么你为什么来这里?
Then why are you here?
我在想你是不是可以帮个忙
I was wondering if you could do me a favor.
唔. 我有...我是伤残人士
Yeah.I've,uh...I've got a disability.
这些是超速罚单
These are speeding tickets.
有很多急诊
A lot of emergencies.
他现在感觉好多了, 但是...世事难料
He's feeling better now,but...you never know.
我想想办法
I'll see what we can do.
你搭档的位子在哪里?
Where's your partner sit?
他家就像是个污水池,但没什么值得一查
Place is a cesspool,but I don't think I need to test for anything.
是的, 浪费时间
Nope,waste of time.
你听说大麻的事了?
You know about the marijuana?
高中我就听说过了
I've heard rumors since junior high.
这个警察表现的很兴奋,因为他确实很兴奋
The cop's acting high because he is high.
他得了-- 军团病,（军团菌科细菌导致肺炎）
He's got--legionnaires' disease.
Joe中枪是件好事
It's a good thing joe got shot.
不然整个警察局会被整垮,街上一片混乱
The whole precinct would have got wiped out.Anarchy on the streets.
需要48小时来检测军团病
Takes 48 hours to test for legionnaire'S.
如果症状符合,只需要两秒钟就可以看出来
And only two seconds to recognize if the symptoms fit
只要看看空调里腐臭的水
while staring at the rancid,unchanged water of an ac unit.
大麻能解释碳氧血红蛋白,肺部阴影及兴奋过度
Marijuana explains the high carboxy,the cloudy lungs,and the happiness.
大麻不能解释,为什么他入院以后情况变得更糟
Pot doesn't explain the fact that he's gotten worse since he was admitted.
为什么我们不能意见分歧?
Why don't we agree to disagree?
事实上, 还是承认吧, 你不愿同我意见一致
Actually,why don't we agree that you'll disagree with me
把他作为军团病治疗?,说了一大通, 但是...
while treating him for legionnaire's?It's not as pithy,but...
我感觉好多了, 药起作用了
I feel a lot better.The meds are working.
心率正常. 碳氧血红蛋白减少. 没有发烧
Heart rate's normal.Cohp levels are down.No fever.
做深呼吸
Take some deep breaths.
你看起来很失望
You seem disappointed.
我很高兴你感觉好多了
I'm glad you're feeling better.
你对警察有意见?
You got a problem with cops?
请别说话
Please don't talk.
照我的经验来看,不喜欢警察的人总有个理由
In my experience,people who just don't like cops have a reason--
我要你别讲话
I need you not to talk.
没有啰音
No rales.
上部本来是阴影的...,我们昨天发现有渗出
these clouded areas of the upperobes...they're the infiltrates we found yesterday.
没有了?
Not there anymore?
正在清理干净,你得过军团菌肺炎
They're clearing up.You had legionnaire'S.
现在好了
Now you don'T.
那么你们没有,唔...在我家里找到什么东西?
So you didn't,um...you didn't find anything at my place?
没有...医学相关的
Nothing...medically relevant.
那么...没什么好担心的, 是吧?
So there's,uh...there's nothing I need to worry about,then?
这次不必担心
Not this time.
你在做什么?
Whatcha doing?
我要让他了解病情
I want to make sure he sees what's involved.
我们发现病情相当严峻
What we found was fairly advanced.
阴影区域在这里, 还有这里
These cloudy areas here,and here.
你肺的这些部分运作失常
These parts of your lungs simply weren't functioning.
现在没有问题了, 对么?
They're okay now,right?
现在一切都正常了?
Everything's okay now?
我很好
I'm fine.
你失明了
You're blind.
我撞到了东西. 并不是说我看不见了
I bumped into something.That doesn't mean I can't see.
我知道这让人恐慌, 但你只认为--
I'm sure it's frightening,but you only think--
Cameron医生穿的是什么?
what's dr. Cameron wearing?
深蓝色裤子, 白衬衫. 黑色的鞋
Dark blue pants,white shirt.Black shoes.
差得不多, 除了裤子, 衬衫, 还有鞋子,你失明了
Ooh,almost.'Cept for the pants,shirt,and shoes.You're blind.
他真的认为他看得见?
he really thinks he can see?
他在器质上看的见,只是他的大脑不能处理了
He can physically see.His brain just can't process it.
会不会是恶作剧?
No chance this is a practical joke?
没可能
No way.
Anton失明表明两侧枕叶都受到了损伤
Anton's blindness indicates damage to both occipital lobes.
肯定是由于外伤所致
Must be from the trauma.
子弹碎片刚刚好击中两片叶的同一处?
Bullet fragments just happen to hit the same spot in both lobes?
中风可能引起anton失明还有异常兴奋
Stroke could cause anton's blindness and euphoria.
克拉基警官在他的大脑里制造血栓,(电影 西城故事)
Office krupke is clotting in his brain.
使用肝素稀释血液,找到血块, 把它弄出来
Start heparin to thin the blood,find the clot,and yank it out.
血块可能在可能在脊椎动脉两侧的上端
Clot would be at the top of the bilateral vertibral arteries.
好极了. Chase...伸进手指,一直摸到你找到为止
Great.Chase...stick your fingers in there,grope around till you find it.
哦, 等等...当你把他变成植物人
Oh,wait...when you turn him into a vegetable,
就会有一场无关紧要的官司
then there's gonna be frivolous lawsuits.
知道怎么做更好么? ,反差核磁共振
You know what would be better?Contrast mri.
有设备吗?
Do we have one of those?
不能做MRI, 如果子弹碎片是导磁的
You can't do an mri.If the bullet fragment's magnetic,
会移位, 把他的大脑绞碎
they'll move and rip his brain apart.
嗯, 扔硬币决定吧
Well,let's flip a coin.
面朝上, 做MRI; 底朝上, 他就死
Heads,mri;tails,he dies.
警用"凯夫拉"防弹衣没有插入陶瓷板
The police issue kevlar vests don't have the ceramic plate insert
不会让子弹粉碎, 只会抓住子弹
that would shatter a bullet,they would just catch it.
所以, 子弹是自己碎散开的
So the bullet shattered on its own.
意味着小脚丫子使用的是,0.38口径中空弹头
Meaning baby shoes was using 0.38 caliber hollow points.
很不幸, 这种子弹是导磁的
Which,unfortunately,are ferromagnetic.
你知道这么多, 真的是太酷了
It's just so cool that you know that.
可以做一个血管造影找到血块
We could do an angio to find the clotting.
浪费时间, 头骨会造出太多伪迹,不会得到一个像样的图像
Waste of time.The skull creates too much artifact.We'll never get a decent view.
- 比不上mri ,- 而且浪费时间
Next best thing to an mri.--And a waste of time.
- 血管造影有可能显示 ,- 天哪, 造反了!
Angio might show--oh,god,it's a coup!
好吧! 去做你的血管造影
Fine!Go do your angio.
浪费完时间后, 我们停尸间见
When you're do wasting your time,meet me down in the morgue.
我们要在你的从股动脉插进一根导管
we're going to snake a catheter in your femoral artery
一直通向你的大脑, 这样可以检测到血块
and up into your brain so we can check for clots.
整个手术中把这个盖上
Keep this on throughout the procedure.
除非大麻已经让你失去生育能力
Unless the pot's already made you sterile.
我工作压力很大, 你不明白的
I have a stressful job.You got no idea.
我见多了你这样的警察
I grew up with cops like you.
一分流氓, 九分的伪君子
One part bully,nine parts hypocrite.
你是怎么搞的?
what is wrong with you?
只是找些乐子
Just having some fun.
这个人病了而且很害怕
That man is sick and scared.
这个人是个不老实的警察
The man's a crooked cop.
也许你不应该再接手这个病例, foreman.
Maybe you should take yourself off the case,foreman.
不必喜欢某人才可以做他的医生
Don't have to like someone to be their doctor.
嘿, 感觉如何, 好伙计?
Hey,how you doing there,buddy?
就躺着别动, 马上会让你复原出院,好让你再把别人吓得屁滚尿流
Just sit still and we'll have you back out there scaring the crap out of people in no time.
高兴了么?
Happy?
血管造影告诉我们什么么?
What did the angio tell us?
你在找什么?
What are you looking for?
我给我妈打过电话, 她不接
I called my mom.She didn't pick up.
血管造影告诉我们什么?
What did the angio tell us?
提示了foreman不应该再接手这个病例
That foreman should be off this case.
他是一个神经科专家
he's a neurologist.
除非你认为病人的视神经在他的脾脏...
Unless you think the patient's optic nerve is in his spleen...
他讨厌警察
he doesn't like cops.
foreman, 警察是我们的朋友
foreman,policemen are our friends.
如果你和我购物时走散--
If you and I ever get separated shopping--
我只是让他老实点
I was just busting the guy's chops.
- 明白了? ,- 只是让他老实点
See?--He was just busting the guy's chops.
Foreman对于解决这个案例很关键
Foreman is essential to solving this case.
医学上讲, 血管造影告诉我们什么?
Medically,what did the angio tell us?
看起来是有一些血块,可能在威利斯环（脑动脉环）附近
Appears to be some clotting,possibly around the circle of willis.
基于症状的恶化, 血块正在增大
Based on the progression of symptoms,the clot is growing.
要切入--
We need to cut into--
"像是有血块",就像说"前方有交通堵塞"
saying there appears to be clotting is like saying there's a traffic jam ahead.
是十辆车连环追尾?,抑或是慢吞吞的公车, 驶在中心道上
Is it a 10-car pileup or just a really slow bus in the center lane?
如果是慢公车, 是一辆血栓还是栓塞车?
And if it is a bus,is it a thrombotic bus of an embolic bus?
看来我把比喻搞的太隐讳了
Think I pushed that metaphor too far.
血管造影无法提供确切信息
Angio can't tell us that kind of information.
噢, 所以你承认这只是浪费时间
Oh,so you're saying it's just a waste of time.
在不杀死他的情况下给出一定的信息
It gave us some information without killing him.
你怎么知道MRI会杀了他?
You don't know that an mri will kill him.
子弹以铁成分为主!
The bullets have a ferrous base!
小铁片困在他的脑子里面, 不会跑到哪里去的
Little tiny pieces trapped in his head.They're not going anywhere.
也许值得用手术把碎片移除
maybe it's worth attempting surgery to remove the fragments.
外科手术不可行,病人正在使用抗凝血剂
Surgeons say inoperable,or the patient's on blood thinners.
除此之外, 倒是完美的计划
Other than that,perfect planning.
你有更好的办法?
You got a better plan?
好的多
Much.
子弹和小脚丫子给Joe的那枪一模一样
Bullets identical to the one that baby shoes popped joe with.
来看看磁性有多大
Let's see how magnetic it is.
有人听到一声--
Did anybody hear a--
我给了他一枪. 他挂了
I shot him.He's dead.
子弹分裂成四片碎片, 没有穿出的伤口
the bullet split into four fragments,no exit wounds.
只用了一半的火药量
Only used a half load of gunpowder.
拿x光片和mri比较是不准确的
We won't be exactly precise comparing the location on an x-ray to an mri.
foreman有多不专业?
How unprofessional was foreman?
和你一样. 他到场了
As him yourself.He's right here.
比平常的糟糕. 比你倒好些
worse than usual.Better than you.
他指责joe是一个坏警察
He berated joe for being a bad cop.
指责还是羞辱?
Berated or humiliated?
我不太肯定, 我没有随身带词典
I'm not sure.I didn't have my thesaurus with me.
他似乎乐在其中
One implies that he took pleasure in it.
我想知道, 是被压抑的气恼, 还是轻佻
I wanna know if it was repressed black anger or just giddiness.
你认为我得病了么?
You think I'm sick?
我觉得正常的反应
I think that an appropriate response
看到老板对着尸体开枪, 不该咧嘴傻笑
to watching your boss shoot a corpse is not to grin foolishly.
我烦透了你的神经质,并不能证明任何东西
But the fact that I've grown bored by your insanity is proof of nothing.
Foreman医生, Chase医生需要你的协助
Dr. Foreman,dr. Chase requests your assistance.
我想象不出你朝尸体开枪,有什么自圆其说的逆向逻辑
I can't even imagine the backwards logic you used to rationalize shooting a corpse.
嗯, 如果我朝活人开枪,不就需要多得多的文书工作了
Well,if I'd shot a live person,there's a lot more paperwork.
那么请你在守灵的时候站在棺材旁边
Then it won't be a problem for you to stand beside the casket at the wake
并解释为什么癌症患者脑袋上有个子弹眼
and explain why a cancer patient has a bullet hole in his head?
这个人把他的身体捐献给了科学
The man donated his body to science.
好吧, 这是个悲剧,如果没有开枪, 他的尸体下一年会
Yes,it's a tragedy. If I hadn't shot him,his body could have spent the next year
留给一年级医学生开膛破肚了
letting first-year med students use the carpool lane.
放好了
He's set.
别开机器, house
Do not turn that on,house.
你生气是因为,我把一颗子弹放到他脑袋里面
You're mad because I put a bullet in his head.
最坏的结果是, 把子弹再取出来
At worst,all I'm doing now is taking it out.
我的错
My bad.
他们得, 嗯, 关掉磁体来修理
They have to,uh,shut down the magnet to fix it.
Mri至少两个星期不能用
Mri is gonna be out of commission for at least two weeks.
嗯, 没关系
Well,it doesn't matter.
很明显我们不能在这个病人身上用mri
We obviously can't use it on this patient.
不能...医院里还有其他的,医生和病人需要用
no...but there are other doctors in this hospital,and other patients.
这有助于解释,为什么买的起这些昂贵的设备
That helps explain how they can afford all the fancy equipment.
我肯定我尽职了
I'm sure i'm pulling my weight.
能不能什么都不做?
Is doing nothing an option?
只是说. 也许血块自己会分解掉
I'm just saying.Maybe the clot will break up on its own.
傻笑看起来已经消失了
The giddiness seems to have gone away.
失明没有
The blindness hasn'T.
用回声波探测他的心脏
Echo his heart.
找什么? 很明显问题是神经学上的
Looking for what?The problem is obviously neurological.
血块是在他的大脑里面,血块的成因可能不是
The clots are in his brain.The source of the clots may not be.
做一个完整的心回波图
Do a complete transthoratic echocardiogram.
也许我们会走运,血块是从心脏那里来的
Maybe we get lucky.Maybe the clots are coming from his heart.
心脏没有问题
heart's clean.
还能做什么?
Where else can we look?
可以超声波检查他的腿,查找深度静脉血栓
We could ultrasound his legs,look for a dvt.
请向下移
I need you to move over.
Joe? 你还好吧?
Joe?You okay?
心动过速. 心率150, 还在上升
Tachycardia.Heart rate 150 and rising.
他在大出血
He's bleeding out.
House降低了血液凝结度, 干得不错
House wanted to thin his blood.Sure did a good job.
血压轰击, 他要休克了
Bp's crashing.He's going into shock.
颅内出血. 需要降低脑压
Intracranial bleeding.We need to relieve the pressure.
需要一个外科小组
We need a surgical team.
Foreman, 出去!
Foreman,get out!
好么, 他完蛋了!
boy,is he screwed!
血液凝结,他是死. 血液抗凝, 他也是死
We clot his blood,he dies.We thin it,he dies.
只有我一个人发现这个好玩?
Am I the only one who finds this funny?
噢,天哪
Oh,man.
我没有病!
i'm not sick!
你听说过有人颅内出血
Did you hear the one about the guy who bled into his brain
结果需要在脑壳上钻一个洞来降压么,太逗了!
and had to have a hole drilled in his skull to relieve the pressure?Hilarious!
有人笑了, 就要死了吗? 太荒唐了
Someone laughs,they're dying?That's absurd.
但不是好玩的
But not funny.
如果我没病,你却把我和病源锁在一起
If I'm not sick,all you're doing is locking me up with the source.
我会被传染得病的, 你就能证明你是对的
I'll get sick,prove you right.
如果你没有病, 这就不是传染性的.,没什么好担心的
If you're not sick,it's not contagious.You've got nothing to worry about.
如果你病了,你们两个就呆在那里,直到我们找出病因
If you are sick,the two of you are staying in there until we find that why.
所以你可能要和那头猪交朋友了
So you might want to make friends with the pig.
好消息是我又可以做mri了
Good news is I can finally get my mri.
不, 你不能!
No,you can't!
你把机器搞当机了!
You blew up the machine!
不是那台便携式的, 笑笑虎
Not the portable one,chuckles.
chase 和cameron 把它带过来,扫描你没有子弹穿孔的脑袋.
Chase and cameron are bringing it to scan your non-bullet-riddled head.
去-你去哪里?
Wh-where are you going?
去办公室. 有活要干
To the office.Got work to do.
你吃饭
Eat your meals.
每半个小时测一下体温,还有服下我让你吃的药
Take your temperature every half hour and any meds i command you to take.
那现在我是一个普通病人了?
So I'm just a regular patient now?
不是
No.
你有自个儿专用体温计
You get your own thermometer.
检查你们的血液
Check your blood.
谁的沉降率上升,就成为foreman的新室友
Anyone with an elevated sed rate gets to be foreman's new roomie.
他应该参与讨论
He should be a part of this.
他是一个病人
He's a patient.
- 他没有失去理智,- 他不客观
He's not irrational.--He's not objective.
他最有动力来诊断病情
He's got the most motivation to get this diagnosed.
不错, 你和他连朋友都不是,何必要在乎?
Right,you're not even friends with him.Why would you care?
扣带回皮层, T2持续衰减
There's an area of increased t2 attenuation in the cingulate cortex.
有点...模糊
Kind of...mushy.
扣带回皮质区控制情感
Cingulate cortex controls emotions.
模糊解释了异常欣快,问题是, 什么导致了区域模糊?
This mushy spot explains the euphoria.Question is,what's causing the mush?
你可能要问神经科专家的问题
Question you might want to ask a neurologist.
Foreman是一个自私的混球,但他是一个神经科专家
Foreman is a selfish jerk,but he's a neurologist,
这间屋子里唯一一个神经学家
and he's the only one who's been in that apartment.
这就是为什么他不能在这里
This is why he shouldn't be here.
如果他在这里, 你就不会叫他混球
You wouldn't call him a jerk if he was here.
他要是在这间屋子里,即使他说错了, 你只能守口如瓶
If you think he screwed up at that apartnt,you'd keep it to yourself.
- 不, 我,- 唔, 我们永远不会知道
No,I--well,we'll never know.
但只要他不在这里, 他就像其他病人一样
But as long as he's not here,he's just like any other patient.
我们可以随意处置他
Which means we can dumpn him all we want.
什么在吞噬这个自私的混蛋的大脑?
What's eating the selfish jerk's brain?
- 西尼罗河病毒还是东方型马脑炎,- 检查foreman的血液
West nile or eastern equine encephalitis--test foreman's blood.
鉴于他是唯一感染上的人
Given that he's the only one who got it,
人到人的传染性不大
person-to-person transmission is
可能 foreman在那家伙家中,染上了一些致命的毒物
less likely than some sort of deadly toxin foreman picked up at the guy's home.
谁要下个去?
Who wants to go next?
你准备牺牲自己,为了一个不把你当成朋友的人
You're ready to sacrifice yourself for a guy who doesn't consider you a friend.
他只是一个病人, 对么?,这是工作
He's just a patient,right?It's the job.
嘿...你哪里也不用去
Hey...you don't have to go anywhere.
Joe的公寓就在楼下的实验室里面
Joe's apartment is right downstairs in the lab.
Foreman带回来了每样东西的样品
Foreman brought back samples of everything.
这算什么, "谁要下一个去?"
What was that,"who wants to go next?"
一种...考验么?
Some kind of...test?
别担心. 你做出了正确的决定
Don't worry.You made the right call.
连Foreman都不知不觉地中了招
Foreman stumbled into whatever it is without knowing.
他比你精明多了
He's way smarter than you are.
该死的 chase!
Damn,chase!
你技术太烂了
You suck at this.
对不起 怪这身该死的衣服
Sorry,it's this damn suit.
我自己能搞定 我会把它扔出去的
I can do it myself.And I'll throw that out.
核磁共振的结果是什么?
What'd the mri show?
我不能参加鉴别诊断,而且连结果都不能知道?
I can't be a part of the differential,and I can't even know what the differential is?
换别的病人你都可以说
You'd tell any other patient what you found out.
核磁共振显示你的扣带皮层有损伤
Mri showed a lesion on your cingulate cortex.
你怎么看?
What's the thinking?
毒素首当其冲
Toxins are in the lead.
较低可能是病毒
Viral's a distant second.
你是否认为那损伤有可能是脓肿?
Do you think the lesion could be an abscess?
只是块小而软的部分 软过--
It's just a small,soft area,more mush than--
脑室内层有炎症吗?
was there inflammation in the lining of the ventricles?
越来越多的信息显示 是的
There was an increased signal there,yeah.
你怎么想?
What are you thinking?
葡萄球菌感染
Staph infection.
毒素导致神经退变 退变导致损伤
Toxins lead to neurodegeneration,which causes the lesion.
不会没有发烧症状
Not without a fever.
那个警察就发过烧
The cop had a fever.
我可能马上就要发烧,或者是他直接传染给我
Mine could be coming.I could have got it directly from him,
或是通过他家的一块脏洗碗布
or a dirty dish towel at his place.
做omaya管埋入手术,将吗啉恶酮直接释放入大脑
Give us omaya reservoirs. Deliver linezolid directly into our brains.
就能治好我们
And we're cured.
甲苯 砷及铅的检测都是阴性
samples tested negative for toluene,arsenic,and lead.
血液呢?
what about the blood?
对西尼罗河热和,流行性甲型脑炎病毒呈阴性
Negative for west nile and eastern equine.
我们必须回到joe的公寓--
We have to go back to joe's apartment--
不准去那个地方,直到我们清楚要找什么
no one goes back to that place till we know what we're looking for.
弄点警用胶带 将门窗封死
Get some of that cop tape.Stick it over the doors and the windows.
我会做足保护措施,感染的机会应该极低
I'll take all the hazmat precautions.The chance of infection is next to nothing.
我数学一向不太好
I was never that great at math.
但是极低还是大于零, 是吧?
But next to nothing is...higher than nothing,right?
他得病不是你的错
It's not your fault he got sick.
如果我们病了就是他的错了
It would be his fault if we did.
我们要直接取一个joe的脑样
We should get a sample directly from joe's brain.
我们不能做活组织检验
We can't do a biopsy.
由于你给他服用肝素,所以出血造成了大面积水肿
There's too much edema from the bleeding because you gave him heparin.
嗯 我想这不是追究责任的时候
Well,I don't think this is the time to be pointing fingers.
我没给foreman用肝素
I didn't give foreman any.
你想给foreman做脑组织活体检验?
You want to give foreman a brain biopsy?
说真的, 谁不想?
Come on,really,who doesn't?
或许这只是葡萄球菌感染造成的神经退变
This could be a simple staph infection causing neurodegeneration.
没有发热症状? 不可能
Without a fever?Not a chance.
- Joe发过烧,- 他体内还有军团菌
Joe had a fever. --He also had legionella.
可能会引起脓肿
The mush might be forming an abscess.
再加上他脑室内层有炎症 这就说得通了
And since there was inflammation of the lining of the ventricles,it makes sense.
葡萄球菌释放毒素 导致神经退变,造成损伤
The staph releases toxins,causes neurodegeneration,causes a lesion.
这是在浪费时间
This is a waste of time.
我们应该将omaya管埋入foreman大脑,并开始启动抗--
We should put an omaya reservoir in foreman's brain and start administering anti--
如果我要和foreman理论,我或许也会直接找他
if I'm gonna be arguing with foreman,I may as well do it directly.
克尼格征阴性
Kernig's sign,negative.
布鲁辛斯基征 单阳性
Brudzinski's sign,single positive.
病人joe luria 远端及近端手臂痉挛
Patient joe luria,distal and proximal arm contractures,
持续4秒
duration four seconds.
葡萄球菌感染在皮肤上极为普遍
Staph infection most commonly presents on the skin.
极为普遍?
Most commonly?
你想把我当任何其他病人来治 就来吧
You wanna treat me like any other patient,do it.
但我知道姓house的人,从不用“极其普遍” 这个词
But the house I know never uses phrases like "most commonly."
你不再笑了
You're not laughing anymore.
不
No.
你认为这是好事?
Think that's a good thing?
有点怀疑
Sorta doubt it.
葡萄球菌在到达你大脑前,会先进入你的心脏 肺 脾 肝 或肾
Staph would be in your heart,lungs,spleen,liver,or kidneys before it gets to your brain.
你的器官没有被感染,并非是葡萄球菌
Your organs are clear.It's not staph.
感染可能只限于脑部脓肿
The infection could be limited to a brain abscess.
你的核磁共振结果就应看得出来
Which I would have seen in your mri.
签个字 这样我才能取一块你的脑样
Sign this so that I can take out a piece of your brain.
让我看看核磁共振的结果
Let me see the mri.
片子上没有显示脓肿
There was no abscess on the image.
那就让我看看
Let me see it,then.
我比较喜欢你笑嘻嘻的
I liked you better when you were jolly.
这是一小时前的片子
Mri was taken over an hour ago.
柔软部分现在可能已经成了脓肿
That soft spot could now be an abscess.
如果是葡萄球菌 你应该在发烧,但你没有!
If it was staph,you'd have a fever.Which you don't!
101.6.
哪个笨蛋给你的?
What idiot gave you that?
在我颅内埋入omaya管,就当葡萄球菌那么治
Put the omaya reservoir in my skull and treat me for the staph.
三角
triangle.
这个呢?
this one?
嗯 圆圈
Uh...circle.
下一个
Next.
Foreman为什么不回答 有问题吗?
Foreman,why aren't you answering?Is there a problem?
嗯 正...正方形
Uh,s-square.
告诉我你的生日
tell me your date of birth.
- 是house吗?,- 是的 下一个
Is that house?--yeah. Next.
还是正方形 他怎么在这儿?
A square again.Why is he here?
因为我的神经专家正在接受手术
Because my neurologist is having surgery.
我想我此刻只是个病人
Thought I was just another patient.
你不相信那屁话 是吧?
You didn't believe that crap,did you?
生日
Date of birth.
将omaya管埋植在顶叶里
The omaya reservoir is inserted in the parietal lobe.
我的空间认知会受影响 而非我的记忆
My spatial recognition is the issue,not my memory.
你在说omaya?
Did you say omaya?
我发誓你说的是活组织检测
I could have sworn you said biopsy.
嘿 我正在扰乱你的脑袋
Hey,I'm just messing with your head.
请说出你母亲婚前的名字
Mother's maiden name,please.
别动我的颞叶, house
Get out of my temporal lobe,house.
有人吗?
Hello?
醒了吗?
Are you awake?
他们说有人得了和我一样的病
They told me somebody was sick like me.
我醒了
I'm up.
你的声音...
Your voice...
你不是我的大夫吗?
aren't you my doctor?
不再是了
Not anymore.
你是那个不喜欢警察的家伙
You're the guy who doesn't like cops.
是的
Yeah.
你看得见吗?
Can you see?
你看不到?
You can't?
什么都看不到
Not a thing.
你失明过一段时间
You've been blind a while.
现在你意识到这个事实了...
The fact that you're aware of it now...
可能是好的征兆
it could be a sign of improvement.
很痛 不是吗?
It hurts so much.Doesn't it?
我还好
I'm okay.
就会痛的
It's gonna hurt.
我的吗啡快失效了
The morphine barely takes the edge off.
我快死了 是吗?
I'm gonna die,aren't I?
你死 我亡 这都不会发生
You die,I die.It's not gonna happen.
为什么不会?
Why not?
你太顽固了所以死不了?
You're just too stubborn to die?
他们取了我的脑样
They took a piece of my brain.
不管我们得的是什么病...,他们都会找出来的
Whatever's wrong with us...they'll find.
你相信祈祷吗?
Do you believe in prayer?
并不真的相信
Not really.
我也是
Neither do I.
我爸爸常祈祷
My dad always prays.
我爸也是
So does mine.
想试试吗?
Do you wanna try it?
试着祈祷?
Try prayin'?
好吧
Okay.
他怎么样?
How is he?
依然没得救
Still dying.
看来你已经练就了另一门技术, 也不错
Well,you've almost mastered another skill,though.That's good.
Foreman活检测的结果
Foreman's biopsy results.
没有发炎症状
Non-specific signs of inflammation.
就这些?
That's it?
我们还做了葡萄球菌化验 阴性,他甚至不是携带者
We also swabbed for staph.Negative.He's not even a carrier.
嗯 至少foreman也错了
Well,at least foreman was wrong too.
是的 如此而已
Yeah,there's that.
我现在能去joe的公寓吗?
Can I go to joe's apartment now?
不
No.
回实验室去
Go back to the lab.
重新检测foreman收集到的所有样本
Start retesting all the samples that foreman collected.
检测什么
For what?
一切
Everything.
细菌 毒素 真菌,一切喜爱侵食大脑的东西
Bacteria,toxins,fungus.Anything that likes to feast on brain.
那有上千种--
That's thousands of--
最好快点
better hurry.
Cameron换衣服,你去盯住foreman
Cameron,suit up.You're gonna monitor foreman.
他就会手痉挛 不久会陷入anton失明
He's on to hand contractures.He'll be in anton's blindness soon.
每小时检查一次 因为当他失明时,他将无法告诉我们
Run hourly checks,because when he does go blind,he won't be able to tell us.
用现有数据做一个时间表,这样就能知道他和joe发病的时间间隔
We'll use the data to construct a timeline so we can see how far behind joe he is.
你怎么还在这儿?
Why are you still here?
你变谨慎了
You're being cautious.
你变得...像常人了
You're being...common.
当你不再说那些屁话--
When you don't give a crap about--
你手下有谁从病人那里感染了癌症?
how many of your guys have caught cancer from their patients?
真发生这种事的时候说一声,到时我们再聊这话题
Let me know when that happens.Then we can have this conversation.
不过是又一个病例 嗯?
It's just another case,huh?
我敢打赌,你就算不做任何措施
Gee,I bet you can even have unprotected sex
和你的癌症病人发生性关系,也不会被传染什么病
with your cancer patients without catching a damn thing.
老兄 我希望做你个工作
Boy,I wish I had your job.
活组织检测没有任何结论
Biopsy showed nothing.
怎么会没有? 你们切了一块我的脑
How can there be nothing?You cut out a piece of my brain.
没有丝毫个人恩怨,我们只是什么都没找到
It's nothing personal.We just didn't find anything.
看在上帝的份上,能不能给他加大吗啡的剂量
Can you up his morphine for god's sake?
已经是最大剂量了 每小时20毫克
He's already maxed out,20 milligrams per hour.
毒素检测呢?
What about toxins?
所有都是阴性
Everything was negative.
炉子上有个橱柜 你们检查过吗?
There was a cupboard above the stove.Did you see it?
我还没检查完所有的食物,但可能是李氏杆菌病
I didn't check all the food,but could be listeriosis.
我们没回去过 往右看
We didn't go back.Follow right.
谁去了?
Who did?
House说我们不应该去 太危险了
House said we shouldn't go.Too dangerous.
答案就在那公寓里 不去才真危险!
The answer's gotta be in that apartment.Not going is too dangerous!
对不起
I'm sorry.
你运气好
You're thankful.
如果house指派的是你而不是我,现在在这儿的就是你了
If house would have pointed at you instead of me,you'd be the one in here.
直视前方 能看见就告诉我--
Look straight forward,tell me when you can see--
回那儿是你的职责! 你是个医生!,哪里有疾病你就要去哪里
it's your job to go back!You're a doctor!You go where the disease is!
你看到光就告诉我
Say when you can see the light.
我就要死了,而你坐在这儿测我的反应速度?
I'm dying,and you're sitting here measuring how fast I go?
你看到光请告诉我!
Tell me when you can see the light!
我视力没问题!
My vision's fine!
你左边的视野缩小了
Your left-side periphery is reduced.
这没什么 我证明给你看
It's fine,I'll prove it.
噢!够娘养的!
Ow! Son of a bitch!
现在你我一样了
Now we're both exposed.
你有两个选择
You got two choices.
你可以去告诉house刚发生的事,然后在这儿得到一个床位
You can go tell house what just happened and get your own cot board in here,
或者你回去趟那公寓...
or you can go back to that apartment...
去救我 救警察 还有你自己
you save me,the cop,and yourself.
不是sspe（罕见亚急性硬化性脑炎）,我查过你给joe注射过的疫苗 无一组相配
it's not sspe.I checked your past vaccinations against joe'S.No batch matches.
血液显示有柯萨奇病毒抗体吗?
Blood show antibodies for coxsackievirus?
伙计们 能让他闭嘴吗?
Guys,could you please shut him up?
他的吗啡用量超极限了
He's over his limit on morphine.
cameron去哪了?
Where's cameron?
她说有事要做 她说很快就回来
She said she has some stuff to do.Said she'd be back soon.
你在干什么?
what are you doing?
Foreman!
停下!我受不了了
Stop!I can't take it!
想象不断地被提醒...你即将承受的痛苦
Imagine being constantly reminded of the...pain you're about to be in.
我受不了了 停下! 停下! 停下 停下!
I can't take it!Stop it! Stop it!Stop it,stop it.
大静脉的吗啡进入他的颈动脉,会导致他心跳停止
Mainline morphine into his carotid could stop his heart!
也能减轻痛苦导致的心肌病
So could pain-induced stress cardiomyopathy.
- 他不是被吗啡杀死就是被痛死,- 你容忍这样的行为?!
Either the morphine kills him or the pain does. --You're condoning this?!
我肯定不会进去阻止他
I'm certainly not going in there to stop him.
这会让你好受些
That'll make you feel better.
Joe有新症状 痛觉过敏
Joe has a new symptom.Hyperalgesia.
感染已经扩散到大脑的痛觉神经
The infection's spreading to the pain center of the brain.
停下来! 停下来!
Make it stop!Make it stop!
他的大脑告诉他他全身都处于痛苦当中
His brain's telling him that his whole body's in pain,
而由于其位置 止痛药不起作用
and because of the location,the painkillers do nothing.
换衣服 在痛感杀死他之前把他弄晕
Suit up.Put the guy in a coma before the pain kills him.
若他用香柏掩盖大麻的气味呢?
What if he used cedarwood to hide the pot smell?
出芽短梗霉菌能在那儿生长
Aureobasidium fungus could grow there.
你发现雪松了吗?
Did you find any cedarwood anywhere?
没有 但或许--,或许什么?
No,but maybe--maybe what?
或许有人回去一趟 再检查一遍?
Maybe somebody could go back,take a second look?
为什么当你生命悬而未知时
And why aren't you pissed off that cameron's playing hooky
你没因为cameron擅离职守而恼怒?
while your life hangs in the balance?
为什么不再有人听我的话了?
Why doesn't anyone listen to me anymore?
我认为你错了
I decided you were wrong.
天 你是笨蛋
God,you're weak.
有人剽窃了你的论文...
Guy steals your article...
告诉你你不是他的朋友...
tells you you're not his friend...
而你仍想为他拿性命去冒险
and you still want to risk your life for him.
Foreman拿用过的针扎了我一下
Foreman broke my skin with a tainted needle.
是的
Yeah.
天 你真蠢 有人想杀你
God,you're weak.Guy tried to kill you.
如果是我第一件要做的事就是,把那一下扎回来 开枪打他
First thing on my list of things to do would be to stab him back.Shoot him.
我抽屉里有把枪
I've got a gun in my desk.
最不想做的就是,跟自己的老板撒谎
Last thing on my list would be to lie to my boss about it
然后顺着那个混蛋的心意
and then give the bastard everything he wanted.
我来这儿不是为了foreman,是为了救我自己
I'm not here for foreman.I'm here to save myself.
即使被针刺了,你受感染的机率也很低
even with a needle stick,your chances of infection are pretty slim.
所以你还穿防护服
That's why you're wearing the suit.
你想到这儿来
You wanted to be here.
他只不过给了你借口
He just gave you the excuse.
那小子要怎么做才能让你恨他?
What does that guy have to do to make you hate him?
把袋子给我
Give me the bag.
- 发霉的洗碗布,- 再做一次葡萄球菌测试
Mildewed dish towel.--To retest for staph.
那是什么 老鼠的排泄物?
What is that,mouse droppings?
仓鼠的排泄物 可能携带蛔虫,可以解释失明
Hamster droppings.Could carry toxocara.Explain the blindness.
那看着像炉渣的东西呢
Now,that I recognize as oven crud.
可能是带有旋毛虫的肉 可以解释高烧
Could be meat with trichinella.Would explain the high fever.
黑麦面包上有什么?
What's with rye bread?
霉变可能导致麦角中毒,这可以解释痉挛
Mold could be responsible for ergot poisoning,which would explain the contractures.
- 有三块,- 所以?
There are three loaves.--So?
你要再进去一次
You're going back in there.
靠外带皮萨过活的人,不会买三块黑面包
Guy who lives on take-out pizza does not buy three loaves of rye.
那未免也想得太远了
That's looking too far into the future.
除非那不是拿来自己吃的
Unless he cares about something a lot more than his diet.
你到屋顶了吗?
You on the roof yet?
是的 在上面了 没看到任何鸟
Yeah,I'm here. I don't see any birds.
吹口哨或什么的
Whistle or something.
招招鸟什么的
Do that come hither thing.
他们来得很快因为这是它们的行为模式
they came that fast because it's their behavior pattern.
Joe一直喂它们
Joe's been feeding them.
现在往下看 看到鸽粪了吗?
Now look down.You see a river of pigeon turd?
嗯... 没有 几乎什么都没有
Uh...no.There's barely any.
不奇怪 因为它便宜
It's not weird,it's cheap.
Joe是个投机取巧的人
Joe's a guy whlooks for the easy way.
没准还从邻居家偷有线电视
Probably been stealing cable from his neighbors.
为什么就不能从“长翅膀的老鼠”,那儿偷肥料?
Why not steal fertilizer from rats with wings?
你看到铁铲或簸箕了吗?
You see a shovel or a dustpan?
嗯 找到一个刮刀 看起来是用过的
Mmm,found a scraper.Looks used.
在一个小桶上
Sitting on a bucket.
桶里全是鸽屎,新型隐球菌绝佳的繁殖地
Bucket full of pigeon crap.Perfect home for cryptococcus neoformans.
是啊
Yep.
真菌通过蝶窦进入大脑
Fungus enters the brain through the sphenoidal sinus,
在那儿造成三重威胁 欣快 失明,及无法控制的疼痛
where it dances its triple threat of happiness,blindness,and intractable pain.
希望这次经历让我们的警察得到教训
Let's hope this experience teaches our cop a lesson.
种大麻的时候别不舍得下本钱,我在屋里等你
Don't cut corners when you're growing your pot.See you back home.
我去过那儿
I was there.
我应该早就发现的
I should have found it.
是啊 你本可以为我们节省很多时间
Yeah,you could have saved us a lot of time.
给我准备两性霉素B和氟胞嘧啶
Get me a flush of ampho b and flucytosine.
我们同时开始治疗
I'll start us both.
我在等实验室确认,house那儿还没有消息
I was waiting for lab confirmation.Haven't heard from house yet.
看他的脑电图
Look at his eeg.
自从我们把他弄晕后,θ波越来越强
Theta band's been increasing steadily since--since we put him under.
他昏迷却依然处在疼痛中
Guy's unconscious,but still in pain.
那个波可以有很多种解释
Theta bands could indicate at least half a dozen different things.
其中之一就是疼痛
One of which is pain.
他不叫了让我们觉得舒服多了,他未必舒服
The fact that he's no longer screaming makes us feel better,not necessarily him.
Chase, cameron怎么样?
Chase!How's cameron?
她没有发昏
She's not giddy.
烧退了 白细胞也有好转
Fever's down.White count's improving.
她对你说了什么吗?
Has she said anything to you?
你指像“我完全理解foreman为何这样做,我并不恨他” 这样的话?
You mean like,"I completely understand why foreman did what he did,and I hold no grudge?"
我所做的...挽救了我的生命
What I did...did save my life.
近来帮忙 别管无菌衣了!
Get in here and help!Forget the suit!
心动过速! 波形宽而多变,像是室性心动过速!
He's tachycardic!Wide-complex looks like v-tach!
不是隐球菌!
It's not cryptococcus!
- 什么?,- House错了, 样本呈阴性
What?--House was wrong.The samples were negative.
那么是什么?
So what is it?
- 不知道!,- 给他注胺碘酮
We don't know!--Give him in the amio.
还有别的线索么?
Do we have any more leads?
那就是了! Foreman!
that was our lead!Foreman!
所以治疗不起作用
So the treatment isn't doing anything.
Foreman! 他心室纤维式颤动
Foreman!He's in v-fib!
没反应 再一次
No good.Hit him again.
别这样 拜托 joe
Come on,man.Come on,joe.
再一次!
Hit him again!
注射肾上腺素
give him an amp of epi!
没反应!
Nothing!
他体内多个系统瘫痪
He's has multiple-system failure.
Foreman.
Foreman
别这样joe
Come on,joe.
Foreman.
Foreman
foreman! 死亡时间
foreman!Time of death.
不
No.
死亡时间
Time of death.
12:26 pm.